Contact

719.419.2222 (Mobile) joshjnap@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ joshuanapieralski (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare Mental Health Public Speaking

Languages

English (Full Professional)
Spanish (Limited Working)

Certifications

Registered Nurse S-130/S-190 Wildland Firefighter Certification

CRRT - Continuous Renal Replacement Therapy Certification TNCC - Trauma Nurse Core Course Certificate of Phlebotomy

Honors-Awards
IRONMAN Class of 2019

Joshua Napieralski

BSN, RNII, CCRN at Texas Health Resources/ Endurance Racing Nutrition Consultant/ IRONMAN Class of 2019

Dallas

Summary

Dedicated, genuine, and patient-driven approach characterize level of care. Advanced training and skilled expertise with critical patients as demonstrated through Burn ICU and ER tenure. Known as a capable leader who can successfully navigate difficult, challenging situations while providing top-level medical care and managing shift teams.

Endurance Race Nutrition Consultant- specializing in tailoring nutrition makeup for athletes of intense, long distance races to include BMI, BMR, Sweat Ratio. Through calculations and a tailored, hands-on approach, nutrition is formulated to achieve maximum success.

Experience

Texas Health Resources Surgical/Trauma/Neuro/Cardiac ICU March 2017 - Present (3 years 6 months)

Dallas, Texas

Trained in Cardiac, Neuro, and Trauma, the STICU is a conglomerate of multiple services that require the top nurses with the most knowledge and experience to handle every patient category.

Parkland Memorial Hospital Burn Intensive Care Unit - Registered Nurse October 2013 - March 2017 (3 years 6 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Responsible for comprehensive acute care in the Level 1 ICU for patients with burns 40% or greater, including resuscitation measures, total wound care, continuous renal replacement therapy, and continuation of treatment.

Key Activities:

Collaborate directly with residents, attending physicians, nutritionists, occupational, physical, and speech therapists to develop optimum care.

Aggressively seek research opportunities to enhance the well-being of the patient and their families.

Leadership: sole charge nurse managing entire shift team with patient, nurse, administrative, research/training & hospital responsibilities; Unit Council advisor

Crisis management: facilitate new admits in critical/unstable situations; lead code emergencies to save patient lives; ensure compliance with established processes

Daily requirements: critical thinking, time management, problem solving

Baylor University Medical Center Emergency Department - Registered Nurse October 2012 - October 2014 (2 years 1 month)

Provided professional, acute levels of nursing care during complex medical situations and critical multi-system issues in the 90-bed, Level 1 trauma facility.

Key Activities:

Partnered with other Emergency Department staff and assumed leadership roles as appropriate to provide optimum patient care in a stressful environment.

Leadership: point of care manager for patients in precarious/serious condition

Crisis management: flexible adaptation to unknown patient circumstances, including psychological and physiological components. Strategically adapted and problem solved to meet changing demands of each shift.

Daily requirements: teamwork, activity prioritization, endurance

Education

Oral Roberts University

Bachelor's Degree, Nursing · (2008 - 2012)